以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好吧，让我先左起点吧
okay let me make a start on the left you
看今天的话题，我们正在做
see the topic for today so we're doing
很好，这完成了我的那种
pretty well this completes my sort of
回顾线性的亮点
review of the highlights of linear
代数所以这是五个讲座和它
algebra so that's five lectures and it
我将跟进这五点
I'll follow up on those five points
因为整洁的部分真的很紧密
because the neat part is it really ties
我可以把整个主题放在一起
together the whole subject I can values
能量a转置决定因素的枢纽
energy a transpose a determinants pivots
他们都聚在一起每个人都给了一个
they all come together each one gives a
试验正定矩阵，从而
test for positive definite matrices so
所有这些我要清楚的是
all that's where I'm going clear is
希望进入一点点
hoping to come in for a little bit of
要问是否有人已经开始的课程
the class to ask if anybody has started
在功课上，得到了朱莉娅
on the on the homework and got Julia
滚动并从汽车获得了肯定
rolling and got a yes from the auto
平地机任何人都没有
grader did anybody is anybody like no
你正抓住朱莉娅的机会
you're taking a chance right Julia in
原则有效但在实践中却是有效的
principle works but in practice it's
我们第一次总是冒险
always an adventure the first time so we
选择这个实验室进行卷积，因为它
chose this lab on convolution because it
是去年最后一次实验室
was the first lab last time last year
并且它不为太多质量要求不惜一切
and it doesn't ask for much mass at all
真的只是创建一个矩阵和
really just creating a matrix and
让自动分级员说是的
getting the auto grader to say yes
那是正确的矩阵所以我们会看到
that's the right matrix so and we'll see
那个矩阵
that matrix
我们会看到这种卷积的想法
we'll see this idea of convolution
在正确的时间适当的时间
in the right time at the right time
这是不是远其信号
which is not that far off its signal
处理，它在第三部分的早期
processing and it's early in part three
这本书好吧，如果克莱尔来了
of the book okay so that if Claire comes
她会回答我的问题
in she'll answer questions otherwise I
猜它会通过电子邮件发送问题
guess it would be emailing questions to
我意识到截止日期还没有开始
I realize that the deadline is not on
你最重要的是你有一个完整的
top of you so and you've got a whole
周末让朱莉娅飞得好
weekend to make Julia fly alright so
我会从数学开始，然后我们开始
I'll start on the math then we had
对称矩阵我可以的值
symmetric matrix I can values of
矩阵，特别对称
matrices and specially symmetric
矩阵和那些具有真实特征值的矩阵
matrices and those have real eigenvalues
我会很快说明原因和正交
and I'll quickly show why and orthogonal
特征向量，我会很快说明原因
eigenvectors and I'll quickly show why
但我想转向新的想法
but I want to move to the new idea
正定矩阵所以这些是
positive definite matrices so these are
那里最好的对称矩阵
the best of the symmetric matrices there
是具有对称矩阵
are symmetric matrices that have
正特征值这是简单的方法
positive eigenvalues that's the easy way
记住正定矩阵
to remember positive definite matrices
他们有正特征值，但它是
they have positive eigenvalues but it's
当然不是我测试的简单方法
certainly not the easy way to test if I
给你一个像那样好的矩阵
give you a matrix like that well that's
我们实际上只能找到两两个
only two by two we could actually find
特征值，但我们想
the eigenvalues but we would like to
有其他测试更容易测试哪些
have other tests easier tests which
将是相当于a
would be which would be equivalent to a
正特征值等等这些其他
positive eigenvalues so these other
这五个测试中的每一个测试中的任何一个
every one of those five tests any one of
这五项测试就是你所需要的
those five tests is is all you need so
让我从这个例子开始，然后问
let me start with that example and ask
你看，然后我会讨论
you to look and then I'm gonna discuss
那五个不同点，但你能
those five separate points but can you
好吧，我的问题是矩阵s
see well my question is is that matrix s
它显然是对称的，它是积极的
it's obviously symmetric is it positive
确定或不好，所以你可以
definite or not okay so you could
计算它的特征值，因为它是两个
compute its eigenvalues since it's two
两点它的能量我会回到那个
by two its energy I'll come back to that
因为那是最重要的一个
because that's the most important one
第二是真正的基本数字
number two is really fundamental number
三个人会要求你把它考虑好
three would ask you to factor that well
那就是你没有
that's you don't
花时间与你做什么你
to take time with that well what do you
认为是正定或不是我
think is it positive definite or not I
看到前排专家说没有
see a expert in the front row saying no
为什么没有答案就是没有
and why is it no the answer is no that's
不是一个肯定的矩阵在哪里
not a positive definite matrix where
是不是让我们失望了
does it let us down it's got all
积极的数字，但那不是什么
positive numbers but that's not what
我们要问的是我们要求积极的
we're asking we're asking positive
特征值正决定因子
eigenvalues positive determinants
积极的枢纽所以它如何让我们
positive pivots so how does it let us
很好，这是容易测试
down well which which is the easy test
看到它失败决定了
to see that it fails determinant the
决定因素是15-16，所以负面和
determinant is 15-16 so negative and
这就是确定的方式
that's what so how's the determinate
连接到每个人的特征值
connected to the eigenvalues everybody
是的，这是两个产品
yep it's the product so the two
它们的特征值当然是真实的
eigenvalues of s they're real of course
他们乘给予
and they multiply to give the
决定因素是负一个这样的一个
determinant which is minus one so one of
他们是消极的，其中一个是
them is negative and one of them is
积极的这个矩阵是不确定的
positive this matrix is an indefinite
矩阵不确定所以我怎么能做到
matrix indefinite so how could I make it
肯定的好，我们可以
positive definite okay just we can just
玩一个例子，然后我们看到
play with an example and then we see
发生这些事情让我们看得很清楚
these things happening let's see okay
还有什么我应该把在地方的
well what shall I put in in place of the
例如，我可以降低四个
five for example I could lower the four
或者我可以提升五个或三个我
or I can up the five or up the three I
如果我添加，可以做对角线条目
can make the diagonal entries if I add
东西到主要的对角线我正在制作它
stuff to the main diagonal I'm making it
更积极的是这样的
more positive so that's sort of
简单的方法以何种号码
straightforward way so what number in
那将是安全的六个好的六个会
there would be safe six okay six would
是安全的，如果我去了5〜6我有
be safe if I go up from five to six I've
当我在这里说时，所以必须这样做
got to do yeah so when I say here
主导决定因素是什么意思
leading determinants what does that mean
这所以这是一个这个词主要手段
that so that's a that word leading means
这意味着我拿一个
something it means that I take the one
一个决定因素它必须通过
by one determinant it would have to pass
那只是决定因素本身
that just the determinant itself would
不要这样让我举个例子
not do it let me give you an example
4号让我减3和减6
no.4 let me take minus 3 and minus 6
那将具有相同的决定因素但是
that would have the same determinant but
它写的决定因素仍然存在
it's write the determinant would still
是18减16-但它没有通过测试
be 18 minus 16 - but it fails the tests
在一个接一个，这通过
on the on the one by one and this passes
这通过逐个测试和
this passes the one by one test and the
两个两个测试，这就是这个
two by two tests so that's what this
意味着这里的主要决定因素来自
means here leading determinants are from
左上角你必须检查结束
the upper left you have to check end
事情，因为你有n个特征值
things because you've got n eigenvalues
那些是最终的测试权利和
and those are the end tests right and
你注意到了连接吗？
have you noticed the connection to
枢纽所以让我们记住这一点
pivots so let's just remember that small
项目是什么将成为枢纽，因为我们
item what would be the pivots because we
没有花很长时间消除
didn't take a long time on elimination
所以这将是针对该枢轴
so what would be the pivots for for that
矩阵344秒井是什么的
matrix 3 4 4 second well what's the
第一枢轴3坐在那里11
first pivot 3 sitting there the 1 1
入口将是第一个枢轴所以
entry would be the first pivot so the
枢轴将是3，第二个是什么
pivots will be 3 and what's the second
转好，或许可以清楚地看到你
pivot well maybe to see it clearly you
希望我采取消除步骤
want me to take that elimination step
为什么我不这样做，所以你会看到它
why don't I do it just so you'll see it
这样消除会减去一些
here so elimination would subtract some
从连续两个II行一个的多个
multiple of Row one from Row two I I
我会留下第一排
would leave Row one alone I would
减去一些倍数得到零
subtract some multiple to get a zero
那里有什么是多重的
there and what what's the multiple
什么是4/3的乘数
what's the multiplier in that was 4/3
4/3次离第二排一排
4/3 times Row one away from Row two
将产生0但是4的4/3倍
would produce that 0 but 4/3 times the 4
这将是16分之三，我们是
that would be 16 thirds and we're
从我认为减去18分之三
subtracting it from 18 thirds I think
我们有三分之二左右的枢轴
we've got two thirds left so the pivots
这是消除或3
which is this in elimination or the 3
和三分之二，当然他们是
and the 2 thirds and of course they're
积极的，实际上你看到了
positive and actually you see the
立即联系
immediate connection
这个枢轴是2乘2的决定因素
this pivot is the 2 by 2 determinant
除以1乘以1的行列式2
divided by the 1 by 1 determinant the 2
通过2个决定因素，我们计算出18-49轴
by 2 determinant we figured out 18-49 ax
16是1乘1的决定因素是3
16 was to the 1 by 1 determinant is 3
确定第二个枢轴是2/3
and sure enough that second pivot is 2/3
这不是我的例子
this is not so by example I'm
说明这些不同的测试
illustrating what these different tests
如果你需要的话，每个测试都是你需要的
and again each test is all you need if
它通过一个测试，它通过它们
it passes one test it passes them all
而且我们还没有找到特征值
and and we haven't found the eigenvalues
让我做能量，我可以做能量
let me do the energy can I do energy
这里好吧，我在说什么呢
here okay so what's this I I'm saying
这真是一个伟大的考验
that this is the really the great test
这对我来说就是a的定义
that for me that's the definition of a
正定矩阵和单词
positive definite matrix and the word
能量进来是因为它是二次方的
energy comes in because it's quadratics
远离动能或势能
away kinetic energy or potential energy
这就是向量X中的能量
so that's the energy in the vector X for
这个矩阵让我计算它X.
this matrix so let me compute it X
转置X所以让我把它放在这里
transpose X so let me put in s here the
原来的，让我投入任何
original s and let me put in an any
向量X所以说XY或X1也许
vector X so say X Y or X 1 maybe
你喜欢XXY更容易吗？
do you like X X Y is easier so that's
这是我们的矢量X转置这是
that's our vector X transpose this is
我们的矩阵s和这里是我们的向量X所以
our matrix s and here's our vector X so
它是x和y的函数，它是纯粹的
it's a function of x and y it's a pure
您知道二次函数吗？
quadratic function can you do you know
当我把它扩散出来时，我得到了什么
what I get when I multiply that out I
得到一个非常简单的重要类型
get I get a very simple important type
我们将函数乘以它
of function shall we multiply it out
让我们看到，所以我乘以那个
let's see so I multiply that by that
首先让我得到3x加4y和4x加6y
first so I get 3x plus 4y and 4x plus 6y
这就是我从这两个中获得的
it's what I'm getting from the these two
而现在我用XY来达到目的
and now I'm hitting that with the X Y
而现在我会看到能量和
and now I'm gonna see the energy and
你会看到永远的模式
you'll see the pattern that's always
什么是数学是什么样的模式
what math is about what's the pattern so
我有x倍3x3x平方+iyx6y
I have x times 3x 3x squared + iy x 6y
这是6平方米，我有x倍4y
that's 6 y square and I have x times 4y
那是4XYz--+iy乘以4x的
that's 4 XY z-- + iy times 4x that's for
更多XY，所以我得到了所有这些条款
more XY so I've got all those terms
每个数字中的每个术语
every every term in every number in the
矩阵给了我一块能量
matrix gives me a piece of the energy
你看到对角线数字3
and you see that the diagonal numbers 3
＆6那些给我对角线3x
& 6 those give me the diagonal pieces 3x
平方+6平方，然后是地壳
squared + 6 y squared and then the crust
但我可能称他们为交叉术语
but I maybe call them the cross terms
那些给我4XY+4XY所以真的是8X.
those give me 4 XY + 4 XY so really 8 X
Y所以你可以称这个东西为8XY
Y so so you could call this thing 8 X Y
这就是我的功能
so that's my function that's my
二次方是我的能量而且我相信
quadratic that's my energy and I believe
大于0的那个让我图
that that is greater than 0 let me graph
让我画出能量的东西
the thing let me graph that energy
好的，所以这是我的功能f的图表
okay so here's a graph of my function f
这里的x和y是X，这里是y和
of x and y here is X and here is y and
当然那是在图上
of course that's on the graph
零等于零等于零等于零
zero zero at x equals zero y equals zero
每个人的功能显然都是零
the function is clearly zero everybody's
得到他的眼睛让我写出这个功能
got his eye let me write that function
再次在这里3x平方6y平方8XY.
again here 3 x squared 6 y squared 8 X Y
实际上你可以看到这就是我的想法
actually you can see this is how I think
关于那个功能如此3x平方
about that that function so 3x squared
显然是把我抬高了
is obviously carrying me upwards it's
不是它永远不会消极的6y平方
not it never goes negative 6y squared
永远不会消极8XY可以去
will never go negative 8 X Y can go
如果x和y相反则为负
negative right if x and y have opposite
迹象表明这将是负面的，但是
signs that that will go negative but the
这些问题是做这些积极的
question is do these do these positive
碎片压倒它并制作图表
pieces overwhelm it and make the graph
像碗一样上升，答案是肯定的
go up like a bowl and the answer is yes
对于正定矩阵这样
for a positive definite matrix so this
是正定矩阵的图
is a graph of a positive definite matrix
能量的一部分正能量
of a part of positive energy the energy
一个正定矩阵所以这是
of a positive definite matrix so this is
能量X转置FX我是
the energy X transpose F X that I'm
图表就在那里
graph and there it is
这一点非常重要
this is important this is important this
是我们喜欢X的功能
is the kind of function we like X
转置X，其中s是正定的
transpose X where s is positive definite
所以功能就像这样
so the function goes up like that this
深学习是这个什么
is what deep learning is about this
可能是你的损失功能
could be a loss function that you that
你最小化它可能取决于一个
you minimize it could depend on a
十万个变量或更多
hundred thousand variables or more and
它可能来自于错误
it could come from the the error in the
训练数据和
difference between training data and
您的
your
而你得到的损失数字将是
and the number you get the loss would be
这样的一些表达好，我会让
some expression like that well I'll make
我能尽快感受到这些话语
sense of those words as soon as I can
我想说的是深度学习
what I want to say is deep learning
神经网络机器学习了
neural Nets machine learning that the
大的计算是最小化能量
big computation is to minimize an energy
我当然要尽量减少能量
is to minimize an energy now of course I
因为我，所以最容易找到
made the minimum easy to find because I
有纯正的方块
have pure squares
也不会在实践发生
well that doesn't happen in practice of
在实践中，我们有线性术语
course in practice we have linear terms
X转移B或非线性是的损失
X transpose B or nonlinear yeah the loss
功能不一定是一件事
function doesn't have to be a thing
那里交叉熵各种各样的东西
cross-entropy all kinds of things there
有一整本可能的字典
there's a whole dictionary of possible
损失功能，但这是模型
loss functions but but this is the model
这是模型，我会成功的
this is the model and I'll make it the
只关注那个完美的模型
perfect model by just focusing on that
在那一部分是好的，顺便说一下
on that part well yeah by the way what
什么会创造会发生什么
what what would create what would happen
如果那是在那里我不应该
if that was in there I shouldn't have
因为我离开这么快就离开了
exited out so so well so quickly since I
把它放在那里让我把它放回去
just put it up there let me put it back
向上
up
我看得更清楚了
I saw it better rather okay
这是最小方块
this is the kind of least squares
一些数据的问题是最小化
problem with some data be minimize that
那么这个家伙的图表是什么？
so what would be the graph of this guy
我可以画出同样的画面
can I just draw the same sort of picture
对于那个功能，它是一个碗是的
for that function will it be a bowl yes
如果我有这个学期所有所做的是
if I have this term all that does is
在x等于0时将其移离中心
move it off center here at x equals 0
好吧，我仍然得到0抱歉我还是去
well I still get 0 sorry I still go
通过这一点，如果这是零
through that point if this is the zero
矢量我仍然会得到0，但这会
vector I'm still getting 0 but this will
把它带到那个会那样的
bring it below that would that would
生产一个像它实际上的碗
produce a bowl like that actually it
就是这样
would just be
碗也是一样的碗
same Bowl the bowl is would just be
转移我可以写那个来表明如何
shifted I could write that to show how
发生这种情况现在就是这样
that happens so this is this is now
零度以下就是这个
below zero this is the that's the
我们追求的解决方案
solution we're after
这告诉我们神经元的权重
that tells us the weights in the neural
网络我只是用这些词而已
network I'm just using these words but
我很快就会对他们有意义
will soon have a meaning to them I want
用其他的话来找到最小值
to find that minimum in other words and
我想找到更多
I want to find it for much more
复杂的功能比
complicated functions than that of
当然，如果我最小化二次方
course if I minimize a quadratic that
意味着将衍生物设置为零
means setting derivatives to zero I just
我可以使用线性方程式
have linear equations probably I can I
可以为此写下所有内容
could write everything down for that for
那件事让我们加入一些
that thing so let's put in some
摇摆不定的非线性东西
nonlinear stuff which which wiggles the
碗让它变得不那么容易
bowl makes it not so easy
我能提前一个月看你怎么找到的
can I look a month ahead how do you find
所以这是数学的重要组成部分
so this is a big part of mathematics
应用数学优化最小化
applied math optimization minimization
一百个复杂功能
of a complicated function of a hundred
千变量是最大的
thousand variables that's the biggest
计算是机器的原因
computation that's the reason machine
学习大问题需要一周的时间
learning on big problems takes a week on
一个GPU或多个GPU，因为你有
a GPU or multiple GPUs because you have
如此多的未知数将超过100000
so many unknowns more than 100000 would
一般来说很正常
be quite normal in general let's just
有展望未来的快乐
have the pleasure of looking ahead for
一分钟后我会回来的
one minute and then I'll come back to
这里的实际生活线性代数是的
real life here linear algebra yeah just
我无法抗拒你如何大声思考
I can't resist thinking aloud how do you
通过这些方式找到最小值
find the minimum by the way these
这两个函数都是凸的
functions both of them are convex so
那是凸的
that is convex
所以我想连接凸函数F.
so I want to connect convex functions F
什么是凸意味着它意味着什么
and what does convex mean it means well
我的意思是图表是这样的
that the graph is like that yeah I mean
不完美它可以，但如果是的话
not perfect it could it could but if if
它是一个二次的凸面式
it's a quadratic then convex means
肯定的，也可能是
positive definite or maybe in the
极端正半明确我会
extreme positive semi-definite I'll have
提到是的但是凸出来
to mention that yeah but but convex
意味着它上升但它可能有
means it goes up but it could have
摆动它不一定是公正的
Wiggles it doesn't have to be just
完美的正方形和线性项但是
perfect squares and linear terms but
一般事物和深度学习
general things and for for deep learning
它将包括没有它将远远超出
it will include none it'll go far beyond
正方形，但它可能不是凸的
quadratics but well it may not be convex
我想这也是真的，是的，所以如此深刻
I guess that's also true yeah so so deep
学习有严重的问题
learning has got serious problems
因为他们可能看起来那些功能
because those functions they may look
像这样，但随后在这里，他们可以
like this but then over here they could
你知道他们可以蘸不凸
go you know non convex they could dip
多一点，你正在寻找
down a little more and you're looking
对于这一点或仍然这一点
for this point or for this point still
我决心告诉你如何找到
I'm determined to tell you how to find
它是如此，或者从如何找到它开始
it so or a start on how you find it so
你在某些时候有合适的遗憾
you're at some point there right sorry
从这个表面的某个地方开始
start there somewhere on this surface
一些X某些矢量X是你的开始
some X some some vector X is your start
x0开始，我们将采取
x0 starting and we're going to just take
希望能顺利地沿着碗向下迈出一步
a step hopefully down down the bowl well
当然，这将是非常美妙采取
of course it would be fantastic to take
一步到那，但事实并非如此
to get there in one step but that's not
会发生什么，这将是
going to happen that that would be
解决一个大的线性系统
solving a big linear system very
昂贵且非常大的非线性系统
expensive and a big nonlinear system so
真的，这就是我们想要解决的问题
really that's what we're trying to solve
我应该是一个很大的非线性系统
a big nonlinear system and I should be
喜欢这张照片
like on this picture
因为在这里我们可以看到
because here we can see where the
最小但是他们只是改变了
minimum is but they just shift so what
如果你有一个起点，你会这样做吗？
would you do if you had a starting point
你想去寻找
and you wanted to go look for the
最小但是什么是自然的想法
minimum but what's the natural idea
计算衍生物
compute derivatives
你已经计算了微积分
you've got calculus on your side compute
第一个衍生品是第一个
the first derivatives so the first
关于X的衍生物，所以我
derivatives with respect to X so so I
会计算F的导数
would compute the derivative of F with
关于X和F的导数
respect to X and the derivative of F
关于Y和十万
with respect to Y and hundred thousand
更多，这需要一点时间
more and that takes a little while and
现在我有衍生物，我该怎么做
now I've got the derivatives what do I
我去的那个告诉我最陡的
do I go that tells me the steepest
在那一点告诉我的方向
direction that tells me at that point
哪条路最快，所以我愿意
which way is fastest way down so I would
按照我会做一个梯度下降我
follow I would do a gradient descent I
将遵循梯度，这是
would follow that gradient this is
所谓梯度所有第一
called the gradient all the first
衍生物称为F的梯度
derivatives is called the gradient of F
梯度梯度向量是a
the gradient gradient vector it's a
矢量当然因为F是一个函数
vector of course because F is a function
我会从很多变量开始
of lots of variables I would start down
在这个方向和能走多远
in that direction and how far to go
这就像百万美元的问题
that's like the million dollar question
在深度学习中，就像在它的时候一样
in in deep learning as when it is it is
它会打到零不，这不是不是
it gonna hit zero nope it's not it's not
所以你基本上你去，直到
and so you basically you go down until
直到他们进去，所以你在旅行
it until they go in so you're traveling
这里是沿着渐变的X和
here in the X along the gradient and
你是不是你不会
you're you're not even you're not gonna
零点你是对的你一切都好
hit zero you're right you're all going
在某个方向，你想要
here in some direction and you want to
去吧，你继续这件事
go so you keep going down this thing
直到它哦，我在这里不是伦勃朗
until it oh my I'm not Rembrandt here
我想你的路径就在那里
I'm there your path down think of
你自己在山上
yourself on a mountain
你正试图走下山，所以你采取
you're trying to go downhill so you take
尽你所能，所以你拿走了
as fast as you can so you take the
最陡峭的路线直到但是但是
steepest route down until but but but
你有你的有色眼镜只是一旦你
you have blinkers on you just once you
决定你进去的方向
decided on a direction you go in that
当然是方向，所以会是什么
direction of course yeah so so what will
恰巧你可以下去了一会儿，
happen you'll go down for a while and
然后它会再次权当转起来
then it will turn up again right when
你得到的排序可能接近
you get sort of maybe close to the
你可能不会去，也可能不是你
bottom or maybe not you you're not going
打到这里，它会错过那个
to hit here and it's gonna miss that and
或许我应该把它画在这里
come up maybe I should draw it over here
无论如何，这就是所谓的一条线
whatever so this is it's called a line
激励决定去那里多远
surge to decide how far to go there and
然后说好的停止，你可以投资
then say okay stop and you can invest a
很多时间或一点时间来决定
lot of time or a little time to decide
在第一个停止点和现在
on that first stopping point and now
告诉我你下一步做什么
just tell me what do you do next
所以现在你现在什么什么在这里
so now you're here what what now
重新计算渐变找到的
recalculate the gradient find the
从那一点开始最陡峭的方式跟随
steepest way down from that point follow
它直到它出现或大约
it until it turns up or approximately
那你就是新的一点，所以这就是
then you're at a new point so this is
梯度下降
gradient descent
这是一个梯度下降的大
that's a gradient descent the big
神经网络深度学习算法
algorithm of deep learning of neural
机器学习网很棒
Nets of machine learning great of
优化你可以说注意到
optimization you could say notice that
我们没有计算二阶导数
we didn't compute second derivatives if
如果我们计算二阶导数我们
if we computed second derivatives we
可能有一个更好的公式可以
could have a fancier formula that could
在这里考虑弯曲曲线
account for the bending the curve here
但计算二阶导数时
but to compute second derivatives when
你有成千上万的
you've got hundreds of thousands of
变量并不是很有趣
variables is is not a lot of fun so most
有效的机器学习是有限的
effectively machine learning is limited
一阶导数的梯度如此
to first derivatives the gradient so
好的
okay
所以这是一般的想法，但有
so that's the general idea but there are
很多很多的
lots and lots of
决定，为什么不那么好
decisions and why doesn't that how well
那样有用吗
does that work
也许是好的方式
maybe maybe is a good way to good
要问的问题这个工作很漂亮
question to ask does this work pretty
你知道还是我们必须添加更多
well you know or do we have to add more
这些想法并不总是很有效
ideas well it doesn't always work well
让我告诉你的麻烦是我
let me tell you what the trouble is I
不要这样，我就像这样
don't so I'm Way off of like this is
这就像三月或其他东西但是
this is like March or something but
反正我说完这句话有啥
anyway I'll finish the sentence so what
这个渐变有什么问题
what's the problem with this gradient
下降的想法，如果你是这样的话
descent idea it it turns out if you're
沿着狭窄的山谷走，我不知道
going down a narrow Valley I don't know
如果你可以想象一个狭窄的
if you can sort of imagine a narrow
谷底朝下，所以这里
valley toward the bottom so so here's
这里是这里的底部是你的
here's the here's the bottom here's your
起点，这就是我的意思
starting point and this is so I mean you
不得不认为这是一个碗所以
have to think of this as a bowl so the
是的，碗是两个
yeah the bowl is the were the two
你能说的特征值是一个和一个
eigenvalues you could say are one and a
碗很长很少
very small number the bowl is long and
你和我在一起很瘦
thin are you with me
想象一个长薄的碗然后是什么
imagine a long thin bowl then what
你采取的情况就是这种情况
happens for that case you you take
最陡的血统，但你越过了
steepest descent but you cross the
山谷，很快你就会爬山
valley and very soon you're climbing
再次让你非常小
again so you take very it's very small
步骤只是来回蹒跚
steps just staggering back and forth
穿过这个并且慢慢地但也是如此
across this and getting slowly but too
慢慢向那里的底部那样
slowly toward the bottom there so that's
为什么事情一定是在你改善
why things have got to be improved you
如果你有，我可以非常小的价值
can if you have I can value a very small
特征值在一个非常大的特征值
eigenvalue in a very large eigenvalue
那些告诉你碗的形状
those tell you the the shape of the bowl
当然，很多情况都会如此
of course and many cases will will be
我可以这样小而大
like that have a small and a large I can
价值，然后你花了你所有的
value and then you're spending all your
时间
time
你快速上升到另一边
you're quickly going up the other side
下来向下，你需要一个新的
down up down up down and you need a new
想法没关系，所以这就是真的
idea okay so that's really so this is
肯定的一个主要原因
one major reason why positive-definite
是如此重要，因为
is so important because
肯定的给出像
positive-definite gives pictures like
这一点，但接下来我们有这个问题
that but then we have this question of
特征值是否相同
are the eigenvalues sort of the same
当然，如果大小的特征值
size of course if the eigenvalues are
一切都等于我的碗就像我们想的那样
all equal what's my bowl like suppose we
假设我有所有假设
suppose all the suppose I have the
身份使得x平方加y
identity so that's x squared plus y
平方是我的功能然后它是一个
squared is my function then it's a
完美的圆形碗将会发生什么
perfectly circular Bowl what will happen
如果我能想象一个完美的
if I can you imagine a perfectly
圆形像在任何任何碗
circular like any any bowl in the
厨房大概是最有可能的圆形
kitchen is probably most likely circular
并假设我在那里做渐变下降
and suppose I do gradient descent there
我完全从某个方面开始
I start at some point on this perfectly
圆形碗我开始下降，在哪里
circular Bowl I start down and where do
我停在这种情况下，做我触底我做
I stop in that case do I hit bottom I do
通过对称性我会如此，如果我采取x
by symmetry I'm gonna so so if I take x
平方加y平方作为我的函数
squared plus y squared as my function
我从某个地方开始，我弄明白了
and I start somewhere I figure out the
渐变是的答案是我会去的
gradient yeah the answer is I'll go
穿过中心所以真的是这样
right through the center so really it's
正正特征值为正
positive positive eigen values positive
明确的矩阵给我们一个碗，但如果
definite matrices give us a bowl but if
特征值相差很远
the eigenvalues are far apart that's
当我们有问题好，我要回去
when we have problems ok I'm going back
我的工作是这个名单，因为你
to my job which is this list because you
真的，这太好了
really this is so nice
是的，你可以吗？
yeah right could you
好的功课可能会出去
well the homework that may be going out
这一分钟是下周中旬
this minute for middle of next week
给你一些练习
gives you some exercises
这个让我做了两件事情一
with this let me do a couple of things a
例如，这里有几个练习
couple of exercises here for example
假设我有一个积极的不同
suppose I have a positive different
矩阵S和正定矩阵
matrix S and a positive definite matrix
如果我添加这些矩阵，则为结果
T if I add those matrices is a result
肯定的，所以有一个完美的
positive definite so there's a perfect
数学的问题，我们希望能回答这样
math question and we hope to answer so
SMT正定大约为S加什么
SMT positive definite what about s plus
T是矩阵正定的好
T is that matrix positive definite okay
我怎么回答这个问题
how do I answer such a question I look
在我的五个测试中，我认为我可以使用
at my five tests and I think can I use
它是什么哪一个会是好的，
it what which one will be good and the
哇和一个不会告诉我太多的是
whoa and one that won't tell me much is
特征值因为特征值
the eigenvalues because the eigen values
s加T不能立即清楚
of s plus T are not immediately clear
来自s和T的特征值
from the eigenvalues of s and T
另外我不想使用那个测试
separately I don't want to use that test
这是我最喜欢的测试，所以我要去
this is my favorite test so I'm going to
用那个能量来解决这个问题
use that what about the energy in so
看看能量所以我看看X.
look at the energies so I look at X
转置s加TX和什么是我的
transpose s plus T X and what's my
在我心中的问题是这样的
question in my mind here is that a
每个X和X的正数或不正数
positive number or not for every X and
我怎么回答这个问题
how am I going to answer that question
把这两个分成两部分
just separate those two into two pieces
对，它在我面前就是它
right it's there in front of me it's
这一次这是什么一个和两个
this one what's this one and both of
那些都是积极的，所以答案是肯定的
those are positive so the answer is yes
肯定是肯定的
it is positive definite yes
你看到能量如何正确我
you see how the energy just was right I
不想计算枢轴或任何
don't want to compute the pivots or any
决定因素就像一个
determinants that would be like a
噩梦试图找到决定因素
nightmare trying to find determinants
对于s加T但是这个没有
for s plus T but this one just doesn't
什么其他将是一个好的
immediately what else would be a good
例如开始与什么有关他们
example to start with what about their
讽刺诗是肯定肯定的
sin verse is that positive definite yes
肯定的，我想问
positive definite and I want to ask
关于它的逆，所以int逆是a
about its inverse so int inverse is a
对称矩阵，它是积极的
symmetric matrix and is it positive
肯定和答案是的，我得到了
definite and the answer yes yes I got
五次测试20％的机会挑选
five tests 20% chance of picking the
正确的一个决定因素并不好
right one determinants not good the
第一个是伟大的
first one is great
第一个是一个好这个
the first one is the good one for this
问题，因为特征值，因此
question because the eigen values so the
回答是是是是这是本征
answer is yes yes yes this is has eigen
因此，s的特征值是多少？
values so what are the eigenvalues of s
在lambda逆1，所以是的，没错
inverse 1 over lambda so yes okay right
是的
yep
那是什么，让我再问一个
what about yeah let me ask just one more
同样的问题假设我
question of this same sort suppose I
有一个矩阵s并假设我乘以
have a matrix s and suppose I multiply
它由另一个矩阵哦好吧
it by another matrix oh well okay
假设是的，我想是的，我猜想
suppose yeah yep suppose I have suppose
我问过你的另一个矩阵
I asked you about s times another matrix
中号
M
那肯定是肯定的
would that be positive definite or not
现在我要告诉你答案了
now I'm gonna tell you the answer the
答案是问题不是
answer is that the question wasn't any
很好，因为那个矩阵可能不是
good because that matrix is probably not
对称的，我只是在处理
symmetric and I'm only dealing with
对称矩阵矩阵必须是
symmetric matrices matrices have to be
在我知道之前，我可以对称
symmetric before I can before I know
他们有真正的特征值，我可以问
they have real eigenvalues and I can ask
这些问题因此不好，但我
these questions so that's not good but I
哦，让我看得好，让我听到你
could oh let's see well let me hear ya
让我让我把它放在一个正交的
let me let me put it in an orthogonal
人以及他们仍然认为不是
guy well they're still that's not
对称，但如果我把它的转置
symmetric but if I put C its transpose
然后我就把它对称哦
over there then I made it symmetric oh
亲爱的，我可能会遇到麻烦
dear I may be getting myself in trouble
在这里，我从一个积极的开始
here so I'm starting with a positive
明确的我正在打击
definite s I'm hitting with an
正交矩阵，它的转置和
orthogonal matrix and it's transpose and
我有点直觉地把我带到了这里
I sort of my instinct carried me here
因为我知道那仍然存在
because I know that that's still
对称的权利，如果我，每个人都会看到
symmetric right everybody sees that if I
转置此Q转置将来
transpose this Q transpose will come
在这里是的Q会去那里它会是一些
here yes Q will go there it'll be some
检查对称现在是积极的
checks symmetric now is that positive
一定哦，是的，我们不能回答这个问题可以
definite oh yes we can't answer that can
我们
we
这是肯定的，所以记住
is that positive definite so remember
这是一个正交矩阵，所以我
that this is an orthogonal matrix so I'm
如果你想让我写它那么
also if you wanted me to write it that
这样我可以
way I could
那些正面的确定性呢？
and what about positive definiteness of
那个东西我认为答案是肯定的做
that thing the answer I think is yes do
你同意这是肯定的
you agree it is positive definite give
我有理由为什么这是积极的
me a reason though why is this positive
确定的大，所以这个词很相似
definite big so that word similar so
这是一个与S类似的矩阵
what this is a similar matrix to S do
你还记得类似的意思
you remember what similar means from
上次它意味着一些m及其
last time it means that some m and its
逆或在这里我们
inverse or here we
它们是什么，所以它是什么
they are and so what's the what's the
与我相似的后果
consequence of being similar what do I
知道一个类似于s的矩阵
know about a matrix that's similar to s
它具有相同的特征值和
it has the same eigenvalues and
因此我们很好或者我可以去
therefore we're good right or I could go
通过这种方式，我能为能量做出这样的能量
this way I could energy I like energy so
让我尝试一个X转Q
let me try that one X transpose Q
转换suX即能量
transpose su X that would be the energy
我试图表明我在尝试什么
and what am I trying to show I'm trying
表明它是积极的，所以我当然是
to show it's positive so of course my as
我看到就像等待一样
soon as I see that like just waiting for
我对QX来说可能就是Y
me to the QX be something called Y maybe
那么这将是我的Y.
and then what will this be my Y
转移所以这个能量就是这样
transpose so this this energy would be
与Y转置相同的Y和什么做
the same as Y transpose s Y and what do
我知道这是积极的，因为
I know about that it's positive because
这是在Y对Y的能量
that's an energy in the Y for the Y
矢量所以这样或那样我们得到了
vector so one way or another we get the
对那个问题回答是，好吧好吧，让我
answer yes to that question ok ok let me
介绍半定的概念
introduce the idea of semi-definite
半定的是边界所以
semi-definite is the borderline so so
我们有什么，我们有三四四
what did we have we had three four four
然后当它五岁时你告诉我
and then when it was five you told me
无限和负特征值时
indefinite and negative eigenvalue when
这是六点，你告诉我两个积极的
it was six you told me two positive
特征值确定了什么
eigenvalues definite what's the
边缘
borderline
什么是它的边界不是
what's the borderline there it's not
它不会是一个整数，但它是
it's not going to be an integer but it's
那我的意思是什么呢？
well what do I mean what am I looking
对于它，边界线是的，所以告诉
for it the borderline well yeah so tell
我再听到十六个以上的声音
me again sixteen over three that sounds
对，为什么这是边界因为
right why is that the borderline because
现在决定因素是零，它是单数
now the determinant is zero its singular
它的零特征值为零
it has a zero eigenvalue there's a zero
特征值，这是半定的
eigenvalue so that's what semi definite
意味着lambda大于等于零
means lambdas are greater equal to zero
等一下零特征值
wait a minute that has a zero eigenvalue
因为它的决定因素是零如何做
because it's determinant is zero how do
我知道另一个特征值是
i know that the other eigenvalue is
这可能是积极的
positive could could the could it be
那是另一个所以这是半
that the other right so this is the semi
确定的情况我们希望，但我们更好
definite case we hope but we better
完成那个推理我怎么知道
finish that reasoning how do I know that
另一个特征值是正的
the other eigenvalue is positive the
跟踪因为加3加16超过
trace because the adding 3 plus 16 over
3无论可能给它什么
3 whatever the heck that might give it
当然给出一个正数和
certainly gives a positive number and
这将是lambda1加lambda2
that will be lambda 1 plus lambda 2
这是跟踪，但lambda2是0我们
that's the trace but lambda 2 is 0 we
从中知道它是单数，所以我们知道
know from this it's singular so we know
其中lambda2为0，因此lambda1必须为0
where lambda 2 is 0 so lambda 1 must be
3加上55在服务拉姆达的
3 plus 5 5 in a service lambda the
lambdas必须是8Messrs3加5和
lambdas must be 8 Messrs 3 plus 5 and
1/3，这是一个积极的
1/3 and so that's a positive
半定哦，如果你想到的话
semi-definite oh if you think of the
正定矩阵作为一些丛
positive definite matrices as some clump
在矩阵空间然后是积极的
in matrix space then the positive
半定的是边缘
semi-definite ones are sort of the edge
他们是那个丛生的边界
of that clump they're the boundary of
那些不完整的丛生
the clump the ones that are not quite
里面而不是外面有两种
inside but not outside either there
他们正躺在边缘
they're lying right on the edge of
正定矩阵让我公正
positive definite matrices let me just
采取有啥约约矩阵什么
take a so what about what about a matrix
所有的故事是什么？
of all ones what's the what's the story
在那一个肯定的所有
on that one positive definite all the
数字是正半或正半
numbers are positive or positive semi
明确或不确定你的想法是什么？
definite or indefinite what do you think
这里还有一个半定的
here one more all one's semi definite
听起来很不错
sounds like a good guess
你知道这个特征值是什么
you know what the eigenvalues of this
矩阵将是30＆0为什么你说
matrix would be 3 0 & 0 why did you say
因为我们只有等级
that because we only have the rank is
是的，介绍那个级别的关键
yeah introduce that key where the rank
是1所以只有一个非零的本征
is 1 so there's only one nonzero eigen
价值然后跟踪告诉我它
value and then the trace tells me it's
这个数字是3所以这是一个
that that number is 3 so this is a
正半正定矩阵
positive positive semi definite matrix
所以所有这些测试都改变了
so so all these all these tests change a
一点半正定特征值
little for semi definite the eigenvalue
能量大于或等于更大
is greater or equal the energies greater
或等于0a转置a但现在
or equal to 0 the a transpose a but now
我不需要哦，我没有讨论这个
I don't require oh I didn't discuss this
但是半确定会允许
but but semi definite would allow
顺便说一下依赖列
dependent columns by the way
你要做的这对我来说是正确的
you got to do this for me right that
矩阵作为转置乘以一个公正的
matrix as a transpose times a just to
看到它是半定的，因为如此
see that it's semi definite because so
把它写成转置是的，如果是的话
write that as a transpose a yeah if it's
排名第一的矩阵你知道怎么做
a rank one matrix you know how to what
它必须看起来像转移是如何
it must look like a transfer was a how
我将参与其中的许多术语
many terms am I going to have in in this
现在我回想起来了
and now I'm thinking back to the very
如果我离开，这个课程的开始
beginning of this course if I pulled off
一般来说这是lambdaone
the pieces in general this is lambda one
乘以第一个特征向量乘以
times the first eigenvector times the
第一个特征向量转置是的
first eigenvector transpose yeah would
只是三个人的向量是的
just be a vector of three ones yeah so
所以这就是通常的情况
so this would be the usual picture that
这与QlambdaQ相同
this is the same as the Q lambda Q
转置这是大的
transpose this is this is the big big
任何对称矩阵的事实和这个
fact for any symmetric matrix and this
是对称的，但它的等级只有一个
is symmetric but its rank is only one so
这使拉姆达二是对于零
that so that lambda two is zero for that
矩阵lambda3对于该矩阵为零
matrix lambda 3 is zero for that matrix
和一个特征向量是
and and the one eigen vector is the
矢量111和本征所以这样
vector 1 1 1 and the eigen so this would
是3次111哦我必须这样做
be 3 times 1 1 1 oh I have to do yeah so
我打算做3次111次1次
I was going to do 3 times 1 1 1 times 1
11但是这给了我333但不是
1 1 but that gives me 3 3 3 that's not
对，我必须将它们标准化
right I have to normalize them that's
对
right
是的，所以这是一个长度的矢量
yeah so that's a vector of whose length
是3的平方根，所以我必须划分
is square root of 3 so I have to divide
通过它除以它然后3
by that divide by it and then the 3
取消三和的平方根
cancels the square root of threes and
我刚刚离开了111111
I'm just left with the 1 1 1 1 1 1
所以我们的建筑有一个矩阵
so there is a matrix one of our building
块类型矩阵，因为它只有
block type matrices because it only has
一个非零的特征值，它的等级是1
one nonzero eigen value it's rank is 1
所以它不能是肯定的
so it could not be positive definite
它是单数但它是积极的
it's it's singular but it is positive
半定因为那个本征值
semi definite because that eigen value
是好的
is positive okay
所以你有了肯定的想法
so you got the idea of positive definite
矩阵再次是所有这五个中的任何一个
matrices again all five of those any one
这五项测试足以表明
of those five tests is enough to show
这是肯定的，所以
that it's positive definite and so
我下周的目标是单数
what's my goal next week is the singular
价值分解和那一切
value decomposition and all that that
引导我们到那就是我们所处的位置
leads us to that's that's where we're
现在准备在SVD好了
there now ready for at the SVD okay have
一个愉快的周末，看到你哦，我看到你了
a good weekend and see ya oh I see you
on Tuesday I guess right not Monday but
星期二，我猜对了，不是星期一
下周二
Tuesday next week